

Having over 17 years of Experience as *Head of IT, Project Manager and Software Engineer*, I have skills in Project Planning, Executing & Controls, with the following areas of Expertise:

- Development and Implementation of ERP Architecture and Business Connectivity (Garments, Accessories, Retail, Production and Distribution).
- Ecommerce, SNS, Custom Software, CMS, LMS, CRM, POS, HRM/Payroll, Data Migration, AI/ML Projects.
- Define and Manage Project Scope, Time, Cost and Quality.
- Complex Projects with Global Implementation.
- Coordination between Cross Functional Stakeholders.

MD ATIQUR RAHMAN, PMP®

Phone:

+880 171 302 8687

E-Mail:

atik3k@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/md-atiqur-rahman-pmp®-4b2b1454/

Skill Highlights

- Garments & Accessories ERP
- Project Management
- Agile, SCRUM, Kanban
- Business Analysis
- Leadership
- Time Management
- Cost Management
- Software Quality Assurance
- Stakeholder Management
- Negotiation
- Risk Management
- Change Management
- Resource Management
- Critical Thinking
- Tech Savvy

Languages

English – Professional Proficiency

<u>IELTS Score: 6.5 (Overall)</u>

Bangla – Native Language

Experience

01/2022 to Continuing ...

Senior Information Technology Project Manager (Sr. Manager) at Dekko Legacy Group

Shimanto Shambhar, 8th Floor, Road No. 2, Dhaka 1205

- Dealing with Dekko Legacy Group ERP Development, Implementation activities. Business: RMG, Accessories, Food, Lifestyle etc.
- Work closely with Business Services teams along with internal and external stockholders where appropriate, to design, develop and deliver proper and proportionate systems to evaluate key activities at both Business and Technology level.
- Development of project team and effective distribution of tasks/Activities among resources.

10/2018 to 12/2021.

Senior Manager, Software Development at Sheba Technologies Limited (A concern of Sheba Group)

8th Floor, Khawaja Tower, 95 Mohakhali C/A, Dhaka-1212

- **BRAC** Al Enterprise ERP Project to outline a software solution to manage end-to-end business operation for Programme.
- Worked on BRAC Skill Development Program (Career Hub), a Priority and Scalable Project for National Implementation.
- Microfinance Project Developed for BRAC BANK SME Collection Dashboard, for Nationwide Implementation.
- Managed e-KYC Project for different Banking and NBFI Organizations.
- Leading Project Management Unit of STL, a subsidiary of Sheba Group having CMMI dev/3, ISO 9001:2015 QMS and ISO 27001:2013 ISMS Certification.

03/2013 to 09/2018

Head of IT at Eicra Soft Limited (A concern of Catharsis Group)

House: 160 (6th Floor), Road: 08, Block: F, Bashundhara, Dhaka-1229

01/2011 to 02/2013

Software Engineer/Project Coordinator at Excel Company Limited House: 16, Block: A, Bashundhara Avenue, Dhaka - 1229

02/2005 to 12/2010

Software Engineer at Bangladesh Internet Press Limited (BIPL)

BTMC Building (3rd Floor), 7-9 Kawran Bazar, Dhaka-1215

Expertise

- Agile, Waterfall
- SCRUM, Kanban
- JIRA, MS Project, Trello
- SDLC, STLC, SRLC
- Project Charter
- Project Management Plans
- WBS, Issues Tracker
- Resource Calendar
- TDD, BDD, FDD
- Task Scheduling
- Risk Register, CR Tracker
- Project Status Report
- Project Lesson Learned
- MS Visio, Balsamiq, draw.io
- User Story, Test Case
- UML, HLD, LLD, DFD
- Process Flow Diagram
- Wire framing, Prototyping
- BRS, BRD, SRS, UAT

Core Technical Proficiency

- PHP, JAVA, Oracle, APEX
- ASP.NET, C#.NET
- JasperSoft, Crystal Report
- reactJS, jQuery, JavaScript
- Django Framework (Python)
- Html, CSS, Bootstrap
- MySQL, MS SQL, Oracle
- AWS, google cloud
- SVN, GIT, Docker
- Nginx (Physical Server), ubuntu
- Android, iOS, Flutter
- SEO, SMM, Digital Marketing
- Selenium, JMeter, Postman

Date of Birth:

18th October 1980

Address:

29/21, Pallabi, Dhaka-1216

Key Projects Experience:

- ERP software for Dekko Legacy Group Readymade garments, Accessories, Food, Lifestyle business and other different SBU.
- LMS & Job Portal with Career Counseling, BRAC, Bangladesh
- ERP for Artificial Insemination programme, BRAC, Bangladesh
- SME Loan management system, BRAC Bank Ltd, Bangladesh
- eKYC Solution, IDLC & United Finance Ltd, Bangladesh
- Premium Customer Solution, Mutual Trust Bank, Bangladesh
- Financial Management Reform Program, MoF, Bangladesh
- Hotel Reservation, Flight Booking & Travel Management System, SaaS Product, Bangladesh
- B2B & B2C Ecommerce platform, SaaS Product, Bangladesh
- StaccatoTrip a Local & Travel website (SNS), California, USA
- Fleetlocate Fleet Management Software, California, USA
- AutoDex CRM & Lead Management Solution, California, USA
- Oiii, Ride Sharing application, Net-Cabs Pty Ltd, Australia
- Parking Administration, Sensor Dynamics Pty Ltd, Australia
- Sidra Brand and Pulse Application, Sidra Hospital, Qatar
- The Daily Q News, Magazine, Multimedia Portal, Qatar

Education

2000-2004

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science & Engineering - American International University Bangladesh

Certifications

PMP: Project Management Professional (PMP)®: 2021. Exam Prep Course Certificate from: 3P Consultancy Limited (2019).

Certified Scrum Master: Preparing for Lean Six Sigma certification.

Targeting to clear it by 2023.

References

Mohammad Abul Kalam Azad

General Manager, SDI | ICT, Dekko Legacy Group Shimanto Shambhar, 8th Floor, Road No. 2, Dhaka 1205 Phone: +880 171 300 2341, Email: azad.cho@dekkolegacy.com

Sarker Mahatab Masud

PMP® | Prince2® Practitioner | Scrum Master SMCTM Sr. Project Manager, BRAC Project Management Unit (PMU) Technology Division, BRAC.

T: 02-9881265 (Ext: 5408) | F: +88023542 | M: +8801708498566 | Email: sarker.mm@brac.net

BRAC Centre | 75 Mohakhali, Dhaka 1212, Bangladesh.